ELOISE SMITH

Seasoned prep cook with 7+years' experience working in high-pressure restaurant kitchens. Flexible working style with the ability to maintain consistently high standardsduring extended shifts. Experienced in mentoring new team members to improve their knife and preparation skills and provide menu orientation. Detailed knowledge of cooking techniques forbread and pastry items.

456 First Street, Baltimore, MD 89012 e.smith@myem a il.com (876)543-2109

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PREP COOK

Au Bon Pain, Baltimore, MD May 2017- Present

- Help prepare approximately 130 plates per night
- Liaise with the chef team to plan how much of each ingredient to prepare per service and ensure adequate stock
- Prepare and chop ingredients under strict time constraints with out sacrificing consistency
- Closely follow precise recipe specifications and ensure that all dishes are fresh and appealing
- Oversee two assistants at the bakery workstation preparing bread dough and pastry products
- Perform routine sanitization of kitchen surfaces and utensils and maintain equipment

PREP COOK

Nando's Peri-Peri, Baltimore, MD February 2014 - May 2017

- Maintained a detailed understanding of menu specifications and ensured familiarity with new additions
- Provided on-the-job training to new team members to increase their practical skills and culinary knowledge
- Correctly stored and labeled ingredientsand performed regular inventory checks
- Used efficient chopping and trimming methods to reduce waste

EDUCATION

High School Diploma Western High School, Baltimore, MD, June 2013

Culinary Arts Diploma

Community College of Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD, June 2013 - February 2014

KEY SKILLS

- Clear written and oral communicator
- Ad vanced kn i fe ski Us, i nc I u d ing deboning and filleting chicken
- Able to work quickly and accurately under pressure
- Excellent teamwork

CERTIFICATIONS

 ◆ ServSafe Food H a nd I e r Certification, 2014